

# **Dario Scalabrin**

**Address**: Rue Louis Favre 4, 1024 Ecublens (Switzerland) **Mob**: +39 3276181071 | **Email**: scalabrin.dario@gmail.com

Dario grew up in a family of entrepreneurs in the north of Italy, which nurtured his curiosity towards innovation, technology, and emerging trends. He studied in one of the largest Italian Innovation Hubs and worked in a Global Fortune 500 company. These experiences fostered the creation of an open-minded and risk-taker young man, who believes in the power of "doing what is right, not what is easy".

#### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

## **EPFL / IMD Business School / UNIL-HEC**

MSc in Sustainable Management and Technology

🛱 09/2021 - Present

Current GPA 5.5/6

Main topics: Entrepreneurship, Innovation, Sustainable Management, Technology, Leadership, Data science and Machine learning

# Ca' Foscari University of Venice x H-Farm

BSc in Digital Management

**iii** 09/2018 - 07/2021

Roncade (Italy)

Final grade: 110 cum laude | GPA 28.4/30

Main topics: Business Administration, Management, Innovation, Digital transformation, Strategy, Data

Science and Marketing

### **WORK EXPERIENCES**

### Assicurazioni Generali S.p.A.

Junior Innovation Consultant

Milan (Italy)

- Activated and supported operations of the Central Innovation Fund
- Monitored KPIs of main innovation initiatives
- Drafted the new strategic innovation plan for the period 2022-2024

### Freement (Entrepreneurial Activity)

Co-Founder and General Manager

- Organized a four-day event for a New Year's Eve trip
- Managed accommodation and transportation for over 150 people
- Handled all the financial resources of the event

### Sca.co s.r.l.

Logistic Coordinator Intern

**iii** 06/2019 - 08/2019

♥ Bottrighe (Italy)

- Recorded and analyzed main issues for delivery delays
- Arranged national deliveries to the main Italian Supermarkets and Wholesalers

### **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCES**

**Google Design Sprint** (04/2021 - 07/2021): Learned about the five-day process for answering critical business questions through design, prototyping, and testing ideas with customers.

**Innovation Champion** (01/2021 - 02/2021): Workshop delivered by Assicurazioni Generali S.p.a aimed at identifying, refining and supporting innovations introduced within an organization.

**H-Farm** (09/2018 - 07/2021): Certificate programs in: Venture Capital, Create a Business Plan, Project Management, Business English, Tech Disruption & Innovative Business model, Presentation Design, Social Media Marketing and Writing in English.

**Ca' Foscari University** (09/2018 - 05/2020): Soft Skill course in Self Awareness and Emotional and Social Competencies.

**Hackathon** (05/2019 & 01/2020): Hackathon contests organized by Novartis and Fondazione Ania.

**English Teacher** (07/2018 - 08/2018): Volunteer in a summer camp with children aged 5-8.

**Boy-scout** (09/2011 - 06/2015): Activities aimed at developing the intellectual, emotional and social potential of the individual as a member of a community.

### **LANGUAGES**

• Italian: native speaker

• English: level C1, IELTS certificate, July 2020

French: level B1, language lessons at EPFL

### **IT SKILLS**

- **Microsoft Office**: Word, Excel, Power Point and Access. *Advanced user*
- **Developer skills**: HTML, CSS, Python, R, Mathematica, SQL and Wordpress

### **REFERENCE**

References available on request